♪If I am gone from this world,
will the dark night collapse?♪
♪If I never return
to guard by your side♪
♪If I seal away our encounter
and erase all trace♪
♪Like endless snow
falling into the deep sea♪
♪This life is but a fleeting illusion,
yet it gave me courage♪
♪Love is a miracle♪
=Spring Over Phoenix Pond=
(Adapted from Qin An'an's
"Spring Over Phoenix Pond")
=Episode 16=
(Marquis Yongping Residence)
Greetings.
What is it you need of me?
Yuan,
we have good news for you.
We found a lead on Consort Great Liu.
That's the first good news.
We have a second.
Yuan,
without you,
the Qi family would already be finished.
The key to the Marquis Yongping Residence
should be given to you.
As for Zhao,
I already sent him back to our hometown
to reflect on his mistakes.
His mother went with him.
From now on,
no one in this household will oppose you.
(The Chief)
The key to the Marquis Yongping Residence
is yours now.
I only came to ask
what really happened in my past life.
Did she not tell you?
You ran errands for her day and night,
I thought
you two were close beyond words.
Just answer the question.
Spare me the commentary.
My past life, huh...
In my past life,
I was with her on our wedding night...
I won the empire.
You were afraid.
So you lied to her and said
you would marry her.
When she was overjoyed
and put on her bridal gown,
you sent her to me
in exchange for your bright future.
This is ludicrous!
I thought
I could learn the truth from you.
I know myself.
I would never do something like that.
Why did she not tell you the truth?
Xiao Yunting.
She hates me.
But she hates you even more.
I know her better than you do.
After she used you to kill me,
you would be the next to die.
If she wanted my life,
I would gladly die by her hand.
What can you do for her?
(Prince Jing Residence)
(Talisman)
When she was overjoyed
and put on her bridal gown,
you sent her to me
in exchange for your bright future.
♪I have loved for your sake♪
(Qi Yuan,)
(the one who hurt you the deepest)
(was me.)
Xiao Yunting,
listen.
You still owe me from our previous life.
You are not allowed to die.
♪Forgetting life, death,
parting, and reunion♪
Was it real
that night?
Xiao Yunting,
our cooperation
is over.
My father found this score in Jiangxi.
It seems to be the work
of Consort Great Liu.
Now Consort Little Liu
has many eyes and ears in the palace.
I fear
that if I send it
straight to His Majesty,
(Qionghua Tune)
the news may leak.
So I ask Your Highness
to look at it first.
This is Consort Great Liu's handwriting.
But the break here is strange.
It looks like a careless omission,
but in truth,
the melody before and after
cannot be joined.
It seems deliberate.
Consort Great Liu must have meant
to send a message through this score.
His Majesty and Consort Great Liu
used to enjoy this game.
They would alter a score
and pass messages to each other.
Look.
These three unusual pauses
are exactly the same
as the marks they used
in the Xuanji Score.
Xuanji Score?
It's a secret record of the rules
for deciphering their musical riddles.
After Consort Great Liu went missing,
His Majesty had an identical pavilion
built in the palace.
That secret record
should be kept in the music room there.
Who is in charge of Siliu Pavilion now?
Consort Little Liu runs it.
You want to go in?
You brought Prince Qi to such ruin.
Consort Little Liu hates you to the bone.
You can get into the palace easily,
but I'm afraid
it will be hard to get out unharmed.
All the more reason
to crack this score.
Only by finding Consort Great Liu
and exposing the truth of their feud
can we clear the Prince Consort's name.
As well as root out
Prince Qi's faction once and for all.
Very well.
I will find a way
to send you into Siliu Pavilion.
You ought to be careful.
Do not let yourself be harmed.
By imperial decree
of the Consort Little Liu,
her elder sister, Consort Great Liu,
has been missing for many years.
The Eldest Princess fasted and prayed
at Baiyun Temple
and moved Heaven
to receive a sign
that a noble lady
with a strong fire-and-earth birth chart
must be brought to Siliu Pavilion
to recite scriptures
to pray for peace.
After checking, Qi Yuan
of the Marquis Yongping Residence
is the perfect match.
So she is to be sent to the palace
at once.
Qi Yuan,
I want to see
what you are capable of.
(Mingyue Pavilion)
Entering the palace was your plan?
I need to find evidence
in Siliu Pavilion.
Tell me where it is.
I'll go find it.
Consort Little Liu hates you to the bone.
Going now
is like walking into a tiger's den.
That is the inner palace.
How could someone of your status break in?
Now that Prince Qi is under house arrest,
this is our best chance
to find Consort Great Liu.
We can't wait.
I have my own way to handle it.
I know
our cooperation is over,
but you're taking too great a risk
on your own.
Qi Yuan,
I'd rather be the blade in your hand
as long as you're safe.
I'm entering the palace
by imperial decree.
Please spare me, Your Highness.
Miss,
this is Siliu Pavilion.
Her Highness has gone to receive
an audience with His Majesty
and has not yet returned.
Please wait a moment.
Is this the former residence
of His Majesty and Consort Great Liu?
(Nanny Liu, steward of Siliu Pavilion)
I hear Consort Great Liu
and Consort Little Liu
are both excellent at the guqin.
Is this the music room?
This is the Tower of Remembrance
His Majesty specially built
for Her Highness.
It's a place
where she mourns her sister.
(Tower of Remembrance)
Over there.
That's the music room.
Her Highness wants you
to wait in the side room.
You are new to the palace,
so do not wander about.
You're flustered and careless.
You have offended an honored guest.
Do you remember the rules of Siliu Pavilion?
Nanny, it's all right.
I was distracted.
Just let her go.
Since the Miss says so,
I will spare you this once.
Get out at once.
Yes.
Please wait here, Miss.
Consort Little Liu will be back shortly.
Thank you, Nanny.
Beauty...
You!
Prince Cheng.
What are you doing here?
Didn't you call me here?
I...
You said
my princess consort had just died
and you feared
I would grieve myself sick.
So you invited me here to meet you.
(Qi Yuan)
Just as I thought.
(Meet me at Siliu Pavilion tomorrow at You hour)
Just as the rumors said.
You're quite fiery.
Miss Qi,
please.
I expected better from the palace.
It's just poison in the liquor.
No better than a country trick.
You have quite the nerve!
Yueying Pleasure House has been destroyed,
and you still owe me for that.
As bold as I may be,
I'm no match for a prince
who barges into the inner palace.
You!
What?
I'll wait for the day
you beg me for mercy on your knees.
Keep dreaming.
So, what do you think
of the palace's poison
compared to your country tricks?
I specially obtained
Lost-Soul Incense from Prince Qi.
Once you breathe in
the flower's fragrance,
your limbs will go weak,
and you'll lose consciousness.
Then you'll be at my mercy.
♪How I wish to hold onto
this fleeting warmth♪
♪How I wish to live this life
only for you♪
♪When memories sink
and the heart settles♪
♪Forgetting life, death,
parting, and reunion♪
♪How I wish to stay
only in the moment with you♪
♪Anchoring myself by your side♪